Lombard has reported its fourth quarter results,
and they were weaker than expected.
Talking about profits, a decline of about 2%
is visible here and let us
talk about the results in detail.  The company's CFO
Gopal Balachandra has joined us to
answer all the questions and Sir,
you are very welcome to this very
special presentation of ours and let the first question
here be about COR where
an assessment of downward treasury was already
given, you had mentioned it and if
we see COR in FI 25, it has declined by about 50 basis
points here and in Q4,
however, we have seen it similar to Q3 FI 25.
But now we see the claim ratios coming higher here.
What is the special reason behind this?  Do
you see this being sustained?  And
if we want to understand the guidance on FI 26 on this line,
what will you give?
This is a very good question.  If I
put this in context, you might have noticed
that in the last earnings call also we had
said the same thing that over the years our
treasury of combined ratio will be a
declining slow.  And if you would have noticed
that two-three years ago our combined
ratio was between 104 to 105.
If you have to see last year, which is
FI 24, our combined ratio ended at
103.3% and this year, which is FI 25,
our combined ratio, which you
said correctly, we ended at 102.8%.  So
clearly the treasury of the Combine is
declining slowly and hence the next FI
26 effort will be that we are able to kind of better
the Combine from the current
levels and that is exactly what
we keep saying at Isolmard that we
will keep looking for how we can right
profitable risk and on that basis we will be able to see further
improvements in the
Combine.  But more than combined, I think we
track the other metrics very closely to see
what returns we can give at the end of the day.
So Fuss is our shareholder.
In the past what we had said was that we will
try and deliver an ROE in the range of 16
to 18%.  Going forward, as
we see incremental improvement,
our treasury ROE on the combine will be
between 18 and 20%.
So that's what we are kind of working towards,
both an improvement in
combined and there for ultimately the returns that
we are able to give to the equity shareholders.
The only thing, of course, we'll
watch for is the direction of the industry
in terms of how it ages.
That will be a very, very key monitorable thing that we will do.
But as it is true for ICbert
clearly the expectation is to improve
combined and there for better ROE.
All right.  Here, if we talk about investment income in this quarter,
sequentially some weakness has been
recorded here.  Investment Income Treasury
How do you see this leadership year in the coming quarters?  Especially
considering that rate cuts will have
an impact.
So this is again a good question because if you
see, we tell all the stakeholders
that the results quarter on
quarter will always be subject to a
lot of volatility and in the general insurance
business, this volatility will be even more because
we collect premiums from the customers on
day one and till our
outflows in the form of claims,
commissions, operating expenses, it takes some
time.  So during this time we
invest those premiums in
various asset classes and earn reasonable returns on them.
So far as return on
investments is a concern.  Ah, the market
opportunity in terms of
realizing investment income can vary.
As you saw, in quarter
four of this year, the equity
market was in that sense relatively compared
to the market situation
in Q3 and the quarters before that.  So,
if you have seen that
our investment income
number for quarter four was actually lower than even
quarter four of last year, the simple reason for this is
that our capital gains number for
quarter four of last year
was approximately above Rs 100-150 crore.
But if you look at the same number in quarter four of
this year, our capital gas number
was in single digit number of roughly about five
to six crores.  So since that had an impact on
the overall investment income, but it is the
nature of our business that you will never find that
in every quarter similar amount
of capital gain is capable of being
realized.  Your question is in terms of how the
trajectory of investment income will
play out given the interest rate regime that is
currently prevailing in the market.  Ah, the
response to this is that we actually had over the
last couple of years when interest rates were
quite high.  At that time, we had kind of put a lot
of our investments in long
dated securities and if you
look at the duration of our portfolio, the
duration of the investment portfolio
which was less than four years 3 years ago, as of today the
duration of the book has become
5.34 years and the yield to maturity
return that we can earn on this duration of
the book, our yield to maturity as of today
is 7.55, so 7.55% is the yield
to maturity that we have in the book.  So here we are,
kind of, rightly poised and placing the
overall investment book, and that should
sustain us even as we look at entering into
FI 26s well.
Okay Gopal ji, please tell me that the
ROE was guided around 16 to 20%.
But the ROE we are already seeing in FI 25 is
around 19%.
But now it is very important that
what would you say about staying in this range
?  Tell me how this will be maintained further.
Then as I said, what we were talking about earlier, the
trajectory of ROE which will be
between 16 to 18%, that was at a
time when our combined
ratio was relatively higher.  As of today,
the fact is that every year we have been able to see an
improvement in combined and as
I said, our effort will be to further
improve the combined ratio
and hence for the ROE range, our
endeavour will be that we are able to
start delivering an ROE of between 18 to
20%.  So that is what we are
kind of targeting and that is what we will very very closely
monitor.
Pishvi Bhai, when I spoke to you Gopal Sahab,
you had mentioned about price hike,
but till now how much price hike have you taken,
how much have you increased the prices and should
we have expectations regarding this now.
So when it comes to price rights, we will have to see its
response on different segments
and I will give this response
on three segments.  If you
talk about commercial lines business that we do
with corporates, which is the current year which is
financial year 2025, we had a lot
of price aggression. There was a
lot of competition in the market in so far as
pricing dynamics are concerned. As
we had said earlier also that
this price competition in commercial lines will not
last long because its exposure is very
high and since the market has to improve
on pricing and in
our last earnings call in January, at
that time we had said that in the January 1
renewals with corporates, we have already seen some
early sign of
price action in terms of pricing
improving and the good news is that in the
April 1 renewals, where
majority of the corporates
renew their policies, we have
seen that there has actually been an improvement
in pricing.  So
on the commercial lines, definitely we have seen
an improvement in pricing going forward
in the year which is FI 26 which kind of
looks very promising and very
positive.  The second segment is Health Now,
if we talk about health insurance, that is
one segment where Ice Lobbard has
invested very actively in
terms of distribution of new
products that we can launch
in the market and equally our focus is on use of
technology and service.  So, if you have seen in the last year, we had kind of launched
a new solution called
Elevate, the feedback of the product
from the customers has been very,
very positive and given that at that time
in quarter two of last year, when we launched
this product, we had said that the
loss ratio range in the retail health indemnity book,
which we are comfortable with, is between 65 to
70% and if you have
seen the loss ratio of the full year for FY25, on retail health
indemnity, that loss ratio has been within
this range of 65 to 70%.
So, at this point in time, I
think we're in that sense quite
comfortable with the way the portfolio is
running.  If required going forward, then we will
not hesitate to take a price increase
on the retail health segment.  The third segment
that comes is motor.  The motor has two parts.
Own damage to third party.  The third party
segment in the industry has been
representing to get a price increase.
Generally, our regulator,
IDAI, in consultation with the government,
notifies third party prices.
So far, we have heard back from the
regulator in consultation with the government on
what that third party premium will be.
Industries are definitely represented
for a price increase.  If he comes then again it
kind of uggs very well for the
market also and specifically for
isom bird also.  So that's how the price
action has been across the three key segments
of commercial lines: health and motor.
Thank you Gopal ji.  You took the time and
answered all the questions today.  So here
we are talking about the results.